Guide to the David Martyn Smith Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
David Martyn Smith papers
1961-1963
MS 1189
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, and other papers relating to the Connecticut Pesticide Investigating Committee. This committee was chaired by Anthony E. Wallace and one its members was David Martyn Smith.
Smith, David M. (David Martyn), 1921-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by David M. Smith in 1965.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
These papers pertain to the Connecticut Pesticide Investigating Committee (the "Wallace Committee") appointed by Governor John Dempsey to investigate pesticide problems and legislation in 1963. David Martyn Smith was a member of this committee, which was chaired by Anthony E. Wallace. Included among the papers are letters (mainly copies of Wallace's correspondence as chairman with the governor and other officials and specialists), minutes and reports of the committee, testimony given by experts before the committee, and subject files of existing and pending legislation, printed matter, newspaper clippings, and notes pertaining to pesticide use, to Rachel Carson's Silent Spring, and to the gypsy moth problem.
These papers were donated to Yale University by David Martyn Smith in 1965. Writings and other papers of Herman Haupt Chapman have been transferred from this collection to the Herman Haupt Chapman Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 134.
Biographical / Historical
David M. Smith (1921-\): educator; B.S., University of Rhode Island, 1941; M.F., Yale, 1946, Ph.D., 1950; instructor, School of Forestry and Environmental Studies, Yale, 1946-1951, assistant professor 1951-1957, assistant dean, 1953-1958, associate professor, 1957-1963, professor, 1963-; Morris K. Jesup Professor of Silviculture, 1967-.
Conservation of natural resources; Environmental protection; Pesticides -- Law and legislation; Connecticut -- Politics and government; Smith, David M. (David Martyn), 1921-; Wallace, Anthony
- Inventory
  - Connecticut Pesticide Investigating Committee papers
    - Correspondence, 1962-1963 August (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1963 February-April (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Testimony, memoranda, and reports, 1963 February-1964 August (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Subject files
      - Existing legislation on pesticides, 1956, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Legislation proposed on pesticides, 1949, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Recommendations for pesticide use, Connecticut, 1953-1963, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Comments on Silent Spring, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - National Wildlife Federation, 1959, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Printed materials and newspaper clippings, 1961-1965, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)